http://www.albemarle.com/privacy-policy

Netherlands
Hungary (Hungarian)
Hungary (English)
Japan
About UsHistoryLeadershipAlbemarle FoundationOur Purpose & ValuesAlbemarle UnlockedLocationsBusinessesLithiumCatalystsBromine SpecialtiesFine Chemistry ServicesSustainabilityInvestorsInvestors OverviewCorporate GovernancePress ReleasesEvents & PresentationsFinancialsStock InformationInvestor ResourcesSustainabilityCareersWorking at AlbemarleBenefits and RewardsJoin Our TeamRecruitment EventsNewsMedia ResourcesLatest NewsTradeshows & ConferencesPress ReleasesEvents & Presentations
Search Keywords
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Date of Last Revision: 09.08.20
Short version
At Albemarle, we take the protection of your Personal Data very seriously.
“Personal Data” means any information concerning your personal or material circumstances that may be used to identify you or other persons. This typically includes information such as your name, email address, telephone number or date of birth, but can also include information such as your IP address, the type of your browser, or websites that you have visited before you have visited our Website. We process your Personal Data to tailor our Website to your interests and improve your User experience, to respond to your contact requests and to evaluate applications that you submit through our online recruitment process. With your consent we use cookies for targeting and performance purposes.
If you would like to receive more information on the processing of your Personal Data, please read the extended version of our Privacy Policy below. If you would like to obtain further information about the cookies that we use on our Website, please read our Cookie Policy.
Extended version
This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) describes how Albemarle Corporation (“Albemarle” or “we” or “us”) processes Personal Data gathered via our website, www.albemarle.com (“Website”). We refer to our Website visitors as users (“Users”).
Table of Contents
WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA?
WHO IS THE DATA PROTECTION OFFICER OF ALBEMARLE?
FOR WHICH PURPOSES DOES ALBEMARLE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?a. Personal Data We Process When You Surf On Our Websiteb. Personal Data We Process When You Contact Usc. Personal Data We Process In Our Online Recruitment Process
HOW DOES ALBEMARLE DISCLOSE INFORMATION?
WHICH SECURITY MEASURES HAS ALBEMARLE IMPLEMENTED?
WHAT HAPPENS IF A CHILD USES THE WEBSITE?
DOES ALBEMARLE USE COOKIES?
HOW MAY THIS PRIVACY POLICY BE CHANGED?
WHAT ARE YOUR STATUTORY RIGHTS?
HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US?
1. WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA?
Albemarle Corporation is responsible for processing your Personal Data on the Website.
2. WHO IS THE DATA PROTECTION OFFICER OF ALBEMARLE?
You can contact our data protection officer at DataPrivacy@albemarle.com, if you have any questions.
Our representative in the EU is: Albemarle Finance Company BV Nieuwendammerkade 1 1022AB Amsterdam, The Netherlands.
3. FOR WHICH PURPOSES DOES ALBEMARLE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
“Personal Data” means any information concerning your personal or material circumstances that may be used to identify you or other persons.
On this Website we process Personal Data for the following purposes:
(A) PERSONAL DATA WE PROCESS WHEN YOU SURF ON OUR WEBSITE
Personal Data That We ProcessWe process we process the following Personal Data for this purpose: The type of your browser, websites that you have visited before you have visited our Website, links you click, IP address and other information that are processed by cookies.
Purpose for Processing of Personal DataWe use cookies or similar technologies to track how you use our Website, to improve our Website and your User experience, and tailor our Website to your interests. For further information, please visit our Cookie Policy.
Storage PeriodPlease check Section 4 of the Cookie Policy (“Which specific cookies does Albemarle use?”) to learn about the storage periods for each cookie.
Legal Justification for ProcessingYour Consent.
Additional Comments You can always visit our Website without disclosing your Personal Data. This requires that you have deactivated the use of cookies.
(B) PERSONAL DATA WE PROCESS WHEN YOU CONTACT US
Personal Data That We ProcessWe process the following Personal Data for this purpose: Name, email address, organization, phone number, country, information about your request and any other information that you provide to us.
Purpose for Processing of Personal DataWe process your Personal Data to respond to your contact inquiries and to provide you with services you have requested and/or customer support.
Storage PeriodWe store your Personal Data only as long as necessary to deal with your contact request, and otherwise only process it in order to fulfill any legal duty to retain copies or to make or defend against legal claims.
Legal Justification for ProcessingPerformance of the contract with you (fulfilling your contact request).
(C) PERSONAL DATA WE PROCESS IN OUR ONLINE RECRUITMENT PROCESS
Personal Data That We ProcessWe process we process the following Personal Data for this purpose: Name, title, gender, address, email address, phone number, date of birth, military details, immigrant status, memberships, academic curriculum, professional qualifications, professional experience, membership in professional organizations, information about your current employment, recruitment date and method, references, prior employment, racial or ethnical data, and photos.
Purpose for Processing of Personal DataWe process your Personal Data to evaluate your application.
Storage PeriodWe delete Personal Data of unsuccessful applicants six months after the recruitment process is finalized, and otherwise only process it in order to fulfil any legal duty to retain copies.
Legal Justification for ProcessingLegitimate interests (Evaluate and consider applicant’s application) or consent (for special categories of Personal Data).
4. HOW DOES ALBEMARLE DISCLOSE INFORMATION?
Albemarle will only disclose your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy. We may disclose your Personal Data to our affiliates of the Albemarle Group as necessary to contact you, provide you with requested services or for administrative purposes. We do not sell your Personal Data to third parties.
We may disclose Personal Data to third party service providers, including but not limited to advisors, advertisers, analytics providers, and investors, for the purpose of conducting our business and providing tailored content to you. We have carefully selected these service providers and entered into data processing agreements, if required by applicable law.
The legal justification for the transfer is legitimate interests (performing our services, using experts to provide our services).
Albemarle will only disclose your Personal Data to other data controllers that process the Personal Data for their own purposes if necessary and permitted by applicable law. Albemarle may disclose your Personal Data to third parties when obligated or permitted to do so by law and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected, or actual unlawful activities, including but not limited to fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or to authorities or law enforcement agencies to comply with legal obligations or to support external audits.
Some of the recipients of your Personal Data listed above may be located in countries outside the EU/EEA that do not offer the same level of protection with regard to Personal Data as required in the EU/EEA and where there is no adequacy decision by the European Commission. In that case Albemarle will ensure an adequate level of data protection by appropriate safeguards, e.g. EU Model Clauses, or BCR certification.
5. WHICH SECURITY MEASURES HAS ALBEMARLE IMPLEMENTED?
We useappropriate technical and organization security measures to protect your Personal Data from unlawful destruction, loss,alteration, unauthorized disclosure of, or access.
6. WHAT HAPPENS IF A CHILD USES THE WEBSITE?
We do not knowingly collect or store Personal Data from anyone under the age of 16 unless or except as permitted by law. If we are made aware that we have received Personal Data from someone under 16, Albemarle will use reasonable efforts to remove that Personal Data from our records.
7. DOES ALBEMARLE USE COOKIES?
Albemarle uses cookies and other similar technologies on the Website that process your Personal Data. For further information, please visit our Cookie Policy or Section 3 of this Privacy Policy.
8. HOW MAY THIS PRIVACY POLICY BE CHANGED?
Albemarle may, in its sole discretion, change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to Albemarle’s Privacy Policy will be reflected here and the date of new versions are posted at the top of this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be communicated on this Website.
Where language on the Website contradicts that found in this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy shall prevail.
9. WHAT ARE YOUR STATUTORY RIGHTS ?
You have a number of rights regarding the processing of your Personal Data by Albemarle. You may
i. Request access to the Personal Data that we process about you,ii. Request rectification of your Personal Data,iii. Request erasure of your Personal Data,iv. Request restriction of Processing of your Personal Data,v. Request to receive your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (right to data portability), orvi. Withdraw any consent with future effect.
Right to Object
Under certain requirements, you may object to certain Processing activities, including Processing for direct marketing
(such receiving commercial emails from us).
Please send your objection to DataPrivacy@albemarle.com.
For more information on your rights and its requirements, please see the information provided by the EU Commission at https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-prote...
Please direct all your requests to exercise your rights above to: DataPrivacy@albemarle.com. You may also the Contact Us form on the Website to submit your request by choosing “Data Privacy Inquiry” in the field “What are you contacting us about?”.
10. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US?
If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please email our data protection officer DataPrivacy@Albemarle.com or contact us at:
Albemarle Corporation4250 Congress Street, Suite 900Charlotte, NC 28209Attention: General Counsel
About LocationsBusinesses Resource CenterNewsCareersContact UsInvestorsSustainability
© 2020 Albemarle Corporation. All Rights Reserved.
Privacy Policy | Cookie Policy | Sitemap
Accept
Albemarle uses cookies on this site with your consent to analyze our traffic and optimize your user experience. For more information, including about cookies we use without your consent and how to opt out, go to our Cookie Policy. By clicking “Accept”, you consent to the use of cookies and confirm that you are 16 or older. You can always opt-out (e.g. by deleting the cookies), however, you may not be able to use the full functionalities of the website.
